Finding Aid for Graduate Program of Medical and Biological Illustration (University of Michigan) Records and Illustrations
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Gerald P. Hodge Illustrations
  - Untitled, 1980 (Box 4)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Norman W. Thompson, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Epithelial, undated (Box 4)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Landis or Dr. Wick)
  - Keratopathy related to antimalarial (hydroxychloroquine) administration in rheumatoid arthritis, 1963; Technique: Pastel on black cardboard with accents of white retouch paint (Box 4)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Duff)
  - Untitled, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Parathyroid adenoma with hemorrhage into the adenoma, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Parathyroid adenoma with hemorrhage into the adenoma, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Parotid papilla, undated (Box 4)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Furstenberg)
  - Correction of mitral valve stenosis, undated (Box 4)
  - Fracture near ext. max. a., undated (Box 4)
  - Arteries of the Nasal Septum, undated (Box 4)
  - Material for Plate #6 (Fig. 11, 12, & 13) for the Gallery (Box 4)
  - Jim Stanley #315380 (Office #46100) (Box 4)
  - Untitled, undated; Technique: Sepia toned photographs, water color added (Box 4)
  - Cutaneous leishmaniasis, circa 1959 (Box 4)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Ruben Kahn)
  - Myocardial Ischemic Injury, Dog Heart, 1972 (Box 4)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Herbert Sloan and Charles M. O'Brien, Senior Medical Student, Department: Thoracic Surgery)
  - Surgical Procedure for Abdominal Aortic Aneurysm, 1969; Technique: Gillott #1000 pen and India ink on Ross scratch board (Box 4)
  - Pancreas and Spleen, 1962 (Box 4)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Charles G. Child III)
  - Subtotal Pancreatectomy. Division of the Jejunum and Inferior Pancreaticoduodenal Artery, and Mobilization of the Entire Specimen, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross Scratch Board (Box 4)
  - Cartoon for the invitation to the special program for the wives, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Right hepatic duct, undated (Box 4)
  - 6 unidentified illustrations (Box 4)
  - Right anest., circa 1984 (Box 5)
  - Left anest., undated (Box 5)
  - Anest., 1972 (Box 5)
  - 7a & 7b, Left Anest., 1972; Technique: Unknown on media paper (Box 5)
  - 8A & 8B Right Anest., 1972; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 5)
  - 2a & 2b Right Anest., 1972; Technique: Unknown on media paper (Box 5)
  - #13 Surgery Right, circa 1983 (Box 5)
  - #4 Surgery Left page, circa 1977 (Box 5)
  - Fig. 16 Surgery, undated (Box 5)
  - 3A & 3B Left Anest., 1972; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 5)
  - 4a & 4b, Right anest., 1972; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 5)
  - #7 Surgery Right page, undated (Box 5)
  - 11a & 11b Left Anest., 1972; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 5)
  - #5 Surgery Right Page, circa 1975 (Box 5)
  - #15 Surgery Right, circa 1977 (Box 5)
  - #11 Surgery Right, undated; Technique: Unknown on media paper (Box 5)
  - Nasal Bones, 1972; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 5)
  - #9 Surgery, circa 1977 (Box 5)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 5)
  - #2 Surgery Left Page, circa 1977 (Box 5)
  - 5A & 5B Left anest., 1972; Technique: Unknown on media paper (Box 5)
  - #14 Surgery, circa 1975; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 5)
  - Rhinoplasty 3, 4., 1973; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 5)
  - #12 Surgery Left, circa 1977 (Box 5)
  - Untitled, 1983; Technique: Carbon and graphite on video paper (Box 5)
  - Untitled, 1983; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 5)
  - Untitled, 1983; Technique: Carbon and graphite on video paper (Box 5)
  - Topography, 1972; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 5)
  - #8 Surgery Left page, circa 1975; Technique: Carbon and graphite on video paper (Box 5)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 5)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 5)
  - #6 Surgery Left Page, 1977 (Box 5)
  - 12 Right (Anest), 1972; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 5)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 5)
    (Requesting Physician: Drs. Dingman and Natvig, Department: Unknown, Milwaukee)
  - Plate 15, 16 Right Page, undated (Box 5)
  - #8 Surgery Left page, undated (Box 5)
  - Lateral nasal cartilages, 1972; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 5)
  - #1 Surgery, undated (Box 5)
  - Untitled, 1983 (Box 5)
  - #10 Surgery Left, undated (Box 5)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 5)
  - #9 Surgery Right Page, circa 1977 (Box 6)
  - #7 Surgery, Right Page, undated (Box 6)
  - #6 Surgery, Left Page, undated (Box 6)
  - #1 Surgery Right Page, circa 1977 (Box 6)
  - LD6-6, undated (Box 6)
  - Method of Eliciting Corneal Reflex, undated (Box 6)
  - Surgical Correction of urinary sphincter, undated (Box 6)
  - Untitled, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Gastroduodenal artery, Splenic artery, 1982 (Box 6)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. J.E. Niederhuber, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Untitled, 1983; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 6)
  - Replaced right hepatic artery, Gastroduodenal artery, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Eyes, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Bookplate, Koala bears with lettering, circa 1982; Technique: Gloss white paper with adhesive backing; process black and pantone 435C (Box 6)
  - Untitled, 1983; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 6)
  - Replaced right hepatic artery, Gastroduodenal artery, 1982 (Box 6)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. J.E. Niederhuber, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan
  - Gastroduodenal artery, Left gastric artery, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Iris Processes, 1967; Technique: Mixed media pastel, water color, colored pencils, acrylics, carbon pencils on a clay coated paper [Video] (Box 6)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Paul R. Lighter, Department: Ophthalmology, University of Michigan)
  - Persistent pupillary membrane, undated; Technique: Water color washes applied on Ross Stipple Board #1 (Box 6)
  - Untitled portrait, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Trigeminal Rhizotomy, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Interventricular Septal Defect, undated (Box 6)
  - Illustration of the principles of the contact blade plate for intrascapular fractures of the neck of the femur, undated; Technique: Carbon dust drawing on Ross Stipple Board #00 (Box 6)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Carl E. Badgley)
  - Choroidal and Collarbutton Melanomas with Detached Retina, Drusen, and Lipofuscin Deposits, undated (Box 6)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Charles Bahn)
  - Retrograde dissection, Aortic lumen, undated (Box 6)
  - The protection of a transplanted kidney..., undated (Box 6)
  - 6 unidentified illustrations (Box 6)
  - Laser Trabecular Photocoagulation for Glaucoma, 1981 (Box 7)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Paul Lighter, Department: Ophthalmology, University of Michigan)
  - Surgical Procedure for Abdominal Aortic Aneurysm, 1969; Technique: Gillott #1000 pen and India ink on Ross scratch board (Box 7)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. John L. Ochsner, Department: The Ochsner Clinic, New Orleans LA)
  - Hereditary Polychromatic Endothelium (1 of 2), 1957 (Box 7)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Harold Falls, Department: Ophthalmology, University of Michigan)
  - Papilledema, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Advanced Glaucoma (Depression of optic disk due to Increased Intraocular Pressure), undated (Box 7)
  - Hereditary Polychromatic Endothelium (2 of 2), 1957 (Box 7)
  - 8 illustrations showing different techniques, undated; Technique: Original sketch in H carbon pencil; Reverse transfer positive transfer onto video paper; H and 2H carbon pencils on video paper; Continuation of D) using stumps, brushes, chamois, and cork; Continuation of E) using lamp black water color and opaque white; 4H, 7H and 9H graphite pencils, lamp black water color, and opaque white on video paper; Soft carbon pencils, 3B carbon dust, lamp black water color, and etched highlights on Ross stipple board #00 (Box 7)
  - Pulmonary valve Stenosis, undated (Box 7)
  - Bookplate: The Cameron Haight Memorial Library, 1978; Technique: Gillott #659 on Essdee British Scraper Board (Box 7)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Herbert Sloan, Department: Thoracic Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Pheochromocytomas, 1987; Technique: Gillott #290 pen (Box 7)
  - 2 illustrations, original and reduced-size reproduction, undated (Box 7)
  - Median Arcuate Ligament Syndrome, undated (Box 7)
  - 2 unidentified illustrations (Box 7)
  - Distribution of parathyroid glands, undated (Box 8)
  - Inferior parathyroid glands, Superior parathyroid glands, undated (Box 8)
  - One of a Series Showing Multiple Extension Technique, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Surgical Procedure for Abdominal Aortic Aneurysm, 1969; Technique: Gillott #1000 pen and India ink on Ross scratch board (Box 8)
  - Trigeminal Rhizotomy: The Temporal Approach, 1964 (Box 8)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Edgar A. Kahn)
  - Roux-En-Y to Hepatic Cyst; Left Hepatic Lobectomy and End-to-End Jejunojejunostomy, 1983 (Box 8)
    (Requesting Physician: Drs. Fredrick Eckhauser and Norman Thompson, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Roux-En-Y to Pancreatic Cyst, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Esophogeal atresia, 1967 (Box 8)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Cameron Haight, Department: Thoracic Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Untitled, 1960 (Box 8)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Kahn (?))
  - Double Aortic Arch, 1961; Technique: Pen and Ink on Scratchboard (Box 8)
  - Mitral Insufficiency Technique of Annuloplasty for correction, 1976; Technique: Carbon & Graphite on Colormatch paper (Box 8)
    (Requesting Physician: Drs. Herbert Sloan and Douglas Behrendt, Department: Thoracic Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Interventricular Septal Defect: Approach from Right Atrium, undated (Box 8)
  - 2 unidentified illustration (Box 8)
  - Gun-Shot Wound of Stomach (Alexis St. Martin), circa 1957 (Box 16)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Thomas Flotte)
  - Gun-Shot Wound of Stomach (7th week), circa 1957 (Box 16)
  - Gun-Shot Wound of Stomach (4th month), circa 1957 (Box 16)
  - Alex St. Martin, June 6, 1822-July 12, 1822; circa 1957 (Box 16)
  - X-Ray, circa 1957 (Box 16)
  - Beaumont, circa 1957 (Box 16)
- Alfred P. Teoli Illustrations
  The Alfred P. Teoli Illustrations series contains 42 illustrations by Alfred P. Teoli. Teoli worked at University of Michigan from 1959-1963. Common subjects include gynecological and obstetrical procedures.
  - Modification of Football Helmet to Prevent Injury to Middle Meningeal Arteries, undated (Box 9)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Richard O. Schneider, Department: Neurosurgery, University of Michigan)
  - Figure 2 Evans, undated (Box 9)
  - Figure 3 Evans, undated (Box 9)
  - Figure 9 Evans, undated (Box 9)
  - Figure 15 Evans, undated (Box 9)
  - Figure 8 Evans, undated (Box 9)
  - Figure 5 Evans, undated (Box 9)
  - Heart sketch, undated (Box 9)
  - Stomach, undated (Box 9)
  - Gonioscopic View of the Iris showing Extension of Pectinate Ligament Strands over Trabeculum, undated; Technique: Airbrush and ink drawing on illustration board (Box 9)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Cornelius H. Stover)
  - Pi Ob/Gyn 4, undated (Box 9)
  - Inf. Alveolar br. (V N.), undated (Box 9)
  - Pi Thor Surg 4, undated (Box 9)
  - Interarterial defects, circa 1966 (Box 9)
  - Examples of Intra-Atrial Defects, circa 1966; Technique: Carbon dust drawing on Ross Stipple Board #00 (Box 9)
  - Skin graft, undated (Box 9)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Graff)
  - VII-10, undated (Box 9)
  - Figure 10 Evans, undated (Box 9)
  - Sketch: Gonioscopic View of the Iris showing Extension of Pectinate Ligament Strands over Trabeculum, undated (Box 9)
  - Man, undated (Box 9)
  - Bayonette forceps with adrenalin soaked sponge, undated (Box 9)
  - Figure 13 Evans, undated (Box 9)
  - Size 12 blade, undated (Box 9)
  - Untitled, 1961 (Box 9)
  - Figure 11 Evans, undated (Box 9)
  - Figure 1 A & B Evans, undated (Box 9)
  - Untitled, 1963 (Box 9)
  - Torso, undated (Box 9)
  - The big COLLER smile, undated (Box 9)
  - Sketches I, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Sketches 4, 1959 (Box 9)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Alexander Barry)
  - Carcinoma, Common P.A., 1963 (Box 9)
  - Pleural space, Parietal pleura, Cancer, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Pancreas, 1962 (Box 9)
  - External oblique m., undated (Box 9)
  - Medial palpebral ligament, undated (Box 9)
  - 1 unidentified illustration (Box 9)
  - Breech Delivery, circa 1960 (Box 16)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Tommy Evans)
  - Superior Mesenteric Artery Embolectomy, 1962 (Box 16)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. William J. Fry)
  - Dissecting Aneurysm of the Aorta, 1963 (Box 16)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. A. James French, Department: Pathology)
  - Femoral Artery, undated (Box 16)
  - Surgical Repair: Atrial Septal Defect, circa 1963 (Box 16)
    (Requesting Physician: Drs. Joe D. Morris and Herbert Sloan)
  - 1 unidentified illustration (Box 16)
- Evelyn Erickson Sullivan Illustrations
  The Evelyn Erickson Sullivan Illustrations series contains 55 illustrations by Evelyn Erickson Sullivan. Sullivan worked at University of Michigan from 1964-1971. Sullivan studied with Max Brödel from 1934-1936.
  - Excision of Urethral Valve and Method of Repair (Figure 3), 1965 (Box 9)
  - Excision of Urethral Valve and Method of Repair (Figure 4), 1965 (Box 9)
  - Excision of Urethral Valve and Method of Repair (Figure 1), 1965 (Box 9)
  - Ear, undated (Box 9)
  - Correction of Urinary Sphincter in a case of stress incontinence (#6 of 7), 1969 (Box 9)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Jack Lapides, Department: Urology)
  - Left temporal bone, 1971; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 9)
  - Ear, undated; Technique: Unknown (Box 9)
  - Correction of Urinary Sphincter in a case of stress incontinence (#3 of 7), undated (Box 9)
  - Correction of Urinary Sphincter in a case of stress incontinence (#7 of 7), 1969 (Box 9)
  - Ureteral transplantation, 1967; Technique: Unknown on ledger paper (Box 9)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 9)
  - Middle meningeal artery, undated (Box 9)
  - Retractor inserted into dural falx, undated (Box 9)
  - Compression of Gasserian ganglion with cotton pledget, undated (Box 9)
  - Incision of dural falx along petrous ridge, undated (Box 9)
  - Ear, undated (Box 9)
  - Brain, undated (Box 9)
  - Excision of Urethral Valve and Method of Repair (Figure 5), 1965 (Box 9)
  - Blephoroplasty, 1970; Technique: Pastel, crayon, and water color on video paper (Box 9)
  - Correction of Urinary Sphincter in a case of stress incontinence (#1 of 7), undated (Box 9)
  - Correction of Urinary Sphincter in a case of stress incontinence (#2 of 7), undated (Box 9)
  - Correction of Urinary Sphincter in a case of stress incontinence (#4 of 7), undated (Box 9)
  - Excision of Urethral Valve and Method of Repair (Figure 2), 1965 (Box 9)
  - Excision of Urethral Valve and Method of Repair (Figure 1), 1967 (Box 9)
  - Excision of Urethral Valve and Method of Repair (Figure 2), 1967 (Box 9)
  - Correction of Urinary Sphincter in a case of stress incontinence (#5 of 7), undated (Box 9)
  - Congenital Atresia of Esophagus, 1964 (Box 9)
  - 6 unidentified illustrations (Box 9)
  - Use of bowel as Urinary Conduit (Fig. 2), 1968 (Box 10)
  - Petrous part of left temporal bone from above, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Blephoroplasty, 1970; Technique: Unknown on video paper (Box 10)
  - Blephoroplasty, 1970; Technique: Pastel, crayons, and water color on video paper (Box 10)
  - Use of bowel as Urinary Conduit (Fig. 3), 1968 (Box 10)
  - Use of bowel as Urinary Conduit (Fig. 5), 1968 (Box 10)
  - Use of bowel as Urinary Conduit (Fig. 6), 1968 (Box 10)
  - Use of bowel as Urinary Conduit (Fig. 1), 1968 (Box 10)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 10)
  - Locations of incisions for renal surgery, 1967 (Box 10)
  - Excision of urethral valve and method of repair (Fig. 3), 1967; Technique: Unknown on ledger paper (Box 10)
  - Cushing's transsphenoidal hypophysectomy, 1969 (Box 10)
  - Olsen Fig. 3, undated (Box 10)
  - Relationship between veins in regions of left kidney, 1967 (Box 10)
  - Fracture of posterior wall of frontal sinus, crista galli, cribriform plate, alae nasi, (with leakage of cerebrospinal fluid), circa 1970 (Box 10)
  - Hemorrhage (in phantom) displacing temporal lobe, 1965; Technique: Carbon dust on ledger paper (Box 10)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Richard C. Schneider, Department: Neurosurgery)
  - 4 unidentified illustrations (Box 10)
  - Implantation of Human Renal Homograft, 1965; Technique: Unknown on ledger paper (Box 16)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Jeremiah G. Turcotte, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Caudal Thrust of cerebellar hemispheres, undated (Box 16)
- Max Brödel Illustrations
  The Max Brödel series contains 16 illustrations by Max Brödel. Brödel taught in the Department of Art as Applied to Medicine at Johns Hopkins University, beginning in 1911 and is considered the "father" of medical illustration as a profession in the United States. Common subjects include sketches for illustrations.
  - Salt Stone, circa 1902 (Box 11)
  - Sutures, undated (Box 11)
  - Gloved, undated (Box 11)
  - Plate VII (Fig. 1 & 2), undated (Box 11)
  - Eye with instruments, undated (Box 11)
  - Face in profile, undated (Box 11)
  - Head (male), undated (Box 11)
  - Head (child), undated (Box 11)
  - Rupture, circa 1908 (Box 11)
  - Anesthetic (reverse transfer), undated (Box 11)
  - Child in profile, undated (Box 11)
  - Hands and instruments, undated (Box 11)
  - Cross-section of head with anesthetic (reverse transfer), undated (Box 11)
  - Hands with skin lesions, 1915 (Box 11)
  - 2 unidentified illustrations (Box 11)
- Emily S. Perry Illustrations
  The Emily S. Perry Illustrations series contains 33 illustrations by Emily S. Perry. Perry worked at University of Michigan University Hospital, 1922-1928. Perry studied with Max Brödel from 1934-1936.
  - 6 mos. placenta, 1926 (Box 12)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Peterson)
  - Fibroid, 1924 (Box 12)
  - Pregnant uterus with tumor, 1924 (Box 12)
  - Saeral Tertoma, 1924 (Box 12)
  - Cerebellar cyst, 1927 (Box 12)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Max M. Peet, Department: Neurosurgery)
  - Ovarian Dermoid cyst, 1925 (Box 12)
  - Neurofibroma of axilla, 1924 (Box 12)
  - Sub occipital decompression, 1923 (Box 12)
  - Double placenta, 1923 (Box 12)
  - Heart valves of dog (enlarged 3 times), 1925 (Box 12)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Herrmann)
  - Colloid degeneration of skin, 1926 (Box 12)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Wile)
  - Sclerosing scleritis or Keratitis, 1923 (Box 12)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Parker)
  - Ventral hernia, 1922 (Box 12)
  - Dermoid cyst on ovary, 1923; Technique: Carbon dust on Ross Stipple Board with Water color (Box 12)
  - Untitled, 1924 (Box 12)
  - Mastoid Op. (1st), 1925 (Box 12)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Caufield)
  - Mastoid Op. (1st), 1925 (Box 12)
  - Leukemic retinitis, 1927 (Box 12)
  - Heart valves of dog, No 51 enlarged 3 times, 1925 (Box 12)
  - Inflammatory foreign body in Omeutum, 1926 (Box 12)
  - General Fibrosis and Subinvolution of Uterus, 1922; Technique: Carbon dust on Ross Stipple Board with Water Color (Box 12)
  - Chronic Subdural Hematoma, 1925 (Box 12)
  - Method of Infiltration for Freezing Fifth Nerve, 1927 (Box 12)
  - 3 unidentified illustrations (Box 12)
  - 7 untitled illustrations done for Dr. Coller (Box 12)
- Elton E. Hoff Illustrations
  The Elton E. Hoff Illustrations series contains 11 illustrations by Elton E. Hoff. Most illustrations in this series are shown as they were reproduced in publication together with the original illustration.
  - Urethral prolapse, 1963 (Box 13)
  - After correction of massive prolapse, rectum is held back..., 1963 (Box 13)
  - Jejunostomy tube, 1964 (Box 13)
  - Pancreatic duct, common duct, and residual pancreas, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Closure of midline xiphoid-to-pubis incision, 1963 (Box 13)
  - Nostril catheter, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Brain: Mild Hydrocephalic, undated; Technique: Photographic emulsion (Box 13)
  - Duodenum and Diverticula, 1963 (Box 13)
  - Pyloric ring, 1963 (Box 13)
  - 2 unidentified illustrations (Box 13)
- Ralph Sweet Illustrations
  The Ralph Sweet Illustrations series contains 8 illustrations by Ralph Sweet (1892-1961)
  - Jejunal transplant, undated (Box 13)
  - Total gastrectomy, undated (Box 13)
    (Department: University of California Medical Center, San Francisco)
  - Early Diagnosis of Carcinoma of the Stomach, Fig. 4, undated (Box 13)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Orville F. Grimes, Department: University of California Medical Center, San Francisco)
  - Wookey Operation: Reconstruction of the Esophagus after Resection for Cancer, undated (Box 13)
    (Requesting Physician: Drs. Orville F. Grimes and H. Brodie Stevens, Department: University of California Medical Center, San Francisco)
  - Achalasia of the Esophagus, undated (Box 13)
    (Requesting Physician: Drs. Orville F. Grimes, H. Brodie Stevens and H. Glenn Bell, Department: University of California Medical Center, San Francisco)
  - Diverticulum of Esophagus, Fig. 4, undated (Box 13)
    (Requesting Physician: Drs. Orville F. Grimes and Binkley, Department: University of California Medical Center, San Francisco)
  - Significance of Hemoptysis in Carcinoma of the Thyroid G, undated (Box 13)
    (Requesting Physician: Drs. Orville F. Grimes and H. Glenn Bell, Department: University of California Medical Center, San Francisco)
  - Significance of Hemoptysis in Carcinoma of the Thyroid Gland Fig. 2, Case 2, undated (Box 13)
- Jeannette Young Illustrations
  The Jeannette Young Illustrations series contains 22 illustrations by Jeannette Young. Young studied with Max Brödel 1926-1928 and worked at University of Michigan 1928-1939.
  - Hip bones, undated (Box 14)
  - Transplantation of the Ureter, 1928 (Box 14)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Hugh Cabot)
  - Foot, 1931 (Box 14)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Maddock Edward Devine, Department: Surgery)
  - Fig 139, 1937 (Box 14)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Cameron Haight)
  - Ob/Gyn 7, undated (Box 14)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 14)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Frank A. Wilson, Department: Heart Station, University Hospital, University of Michigan
  - Abdominal Surgery 24, undated (Box 14)
  - Peritoneum, undated (Box 14)
  - Ob/Gyn 25, undated (Box 14)
  - Transplantation of the Ureter, 1928 (Box 14)
  - Transplantation of the Ureter (Figs. 4 & 6), 1928 (Box 14)
  - Vascular visceral fascia, undated (Box 14)
  - Umbilical vesicle fascia, undated (Box 14)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 14)
  - Tracheal Compression Caused By Aortic Aneurysm, circa 1935; Technique: Carbon dust on Stipple Board (Box 14)
  - Encephalomeningocele (protrusion of brain substance, covered with membranes, through a defect in the skull), circa 1935 (Box 14)
  - Sagittal Section of Heart, undated (Box 14)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 14)
  - Fascial Plane of Neck, undated (Box 14)
  - 3 unidentified illustrations (Box 14)
  - Line for local infiltration of anesthetic for phrenicectomy, 1929; Technique: Unknown on Ross Stipple Board No. 00 (Box 16)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. John Alexander, Department: Thoracic Surgery, University of Michigan)
- Neil Hardy Illustrations
  The Neil Hardy Illustrations series contains 14 illustrations by Hardy.
  - Some Pitfalls of X-Ray Diagnosis in Acute Recurrent Pancreatitis, undated (Box 14)
  - Ryan, Plate 2, undated (Box 14)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Ryan)
  - Untitled, undated; Technique: Unknown on textured acetate (Box 14)
  - Mouth-to-mouth respiration, undated (Box 14)
  - Using Ophthalmoscope, undated (Box 14)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Piemme)
  - Fixation of fractures, undated (Box 14)
  - Vertical Compression Injury, undated (Box 14)
  - Multi-organ injury produced by one bullet, undated (Box 14)
  - Body Fluids, undated (Box 14)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Grant)
  - Autonomic Hyperreflexia, undated (Box 14)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Feustal)
  - Renal Biopsy, undated (Box 14)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Fennel)